What the...?
怎么回...？
Ah... no... no! No!
啊...不...不！不要！
Day of the Daleks
(Whopix fan edit)
Dalek 之日
(粉丝剪辑版)
(基于 opensubtitles.org 字幕)
Sincro: wyxchari
Doctor, why don't you take a break?
博士，你为什么不休息一下？
It's maddening, you know. So nearly there.
很让人抓狂啊，知道吧。很接近了啊
If I could only cut out their override
on the dematerialisation circuit.
只要我能切断他们的优先控制权就好了，他们锁住了反物质化电路
Let me see those figures.
让我看看那些图纸
Doctor?
博士？
I thought the TARDIS was working again.
我以为 TARDIS 又可以用了
What gave you that idea?
谁给了你这样的想法？
Oh, being dragged off to an alien planet
five hundred years in the future, for example.
哦，比如说，我被拖到了五百年后的一颗外星
Oh, you know - all that business
with the miners and the colonists.
你知道的，都是矿工啊殖民者啊那些事
My dear Jo, the TARDIS was being operated then
under remote control by the High Council of the Time Lords.
亲爱的 Jo, TARDIS 那时候是被时间领主最高议会远程控制着呢
Well, if it worked for them...
如果对他们来说这可以用...
I don't want it to work for them.
I want it to work for me.
我不想它对他们可以用，我想要它对我可以用
No-one's going to turn me into
an interplanetary puppet.
任何人别想把我变成一个星际傀儡
Yes, of course. Why didn't I think of that before?
啊，是了，我之前怎么没有想到过？
Yes, of course. I remember now.
是的，当然，我想起来了
Look, don't worry, my dear.
I know you're alarmed but you needn't be.
看，别担心，亲爱的。我知道你受惊了，但没有必要
Yes, well I think that should do it.
Why on Earth I never realised that...
是的，我想这应该可以了。为什么我从来没有意识到...
Oh no! What are you doing here?
噢！你在这里做什么？
Well, I'm not here. Don't worry.
其实，我没在这里。别担心
Well, that is, in a sense, er, I am here,
but, erm, you are not there.
不过，其实是，某种程度上，我在这里，但是，呃，你不在那里
Er... yes, well, it's a bit difficult
to explain really.
呃...这个，的确有点难解释
This won't do at all!
We can't have two of us running about.
完全说不通！不可能有两个我在这里乱转！
Yes, well don't worry. It will all sor...
是的，不过不用担心。一切都会弄清...
Doctor! What happened?
博士！发生了什么？
Well, it's a very complicated thing - time - Jo.
这个, 它是一件很复杂的事情 - 时间 - Jo
Once you've begun tampering with it,
the oddest things start happening.
一旦你开始玩弄它，奇怪的事情就会出现
But there was another you and another... me.
但刚才有另一个你和另一个...我
Well, where've they gone?
他们都去哪儿了？
Back into their own time stream, of course.
Or do I mean forward?
当然是退回到他们自己的时间流去了，或者不是退回是前进？
But, Doctor, I don't understand...
但是，博士，我搞不明白...
Look, Jo. Don't worry about it. It was a freak affect.
It's very unlikely to happen again.
听着, Jo, 别担心。这是一个奇怪的现象，非常不可能再次发生
Hold that and give me those papers.
拿着这个，把纸夹给我
Ah, Doctor. Glad you're still here.
啊，博士，很高兴你还在这里
I need your help.
我需要你的帮助
Sorry, Brigadier. I'm busy.
对不起，准将，我正忙
Yeah, so am I, Doctor, so am I. /?
是，我也是，博士，我也是
Now then, you've heard of Sir Reginald Styles?
现在看看，你听说过 Reginald Styles 爵士吧？
No, can't say that I have.
没，不能说我听过
Well isn't he the chief representative at the UN?
但他不是驻联合国首席代表吗？
That's right - key figure at the latest
summit conference.
正是 - 是最近的峰会上的关键人物
My dear chap, I'm a scientist. Not a politician.
我亲爱的小伙，我是个科学家，不是个政客
You know, Doctor, if you... didn't spend so much time.../?
知道吗，博士，如果你...没有花那么多时间...
...tinkering around with this wretched contraption,
...摆弄这个可怜的装置的话
you'd realise just how bad
the international situation's become.
你就会意识到国际形势变得多么糟糕
Humans are always squabbling over something, Brigadier.
人类总是会为点什么事争论不休, 准将
Yes, well, this particular squabble looks like
ending up in a third world war.
是的, 好吧, 这一次的争吵看起来像是要导致第三次世界大战似的
The Chinese delegation have refused to attend.
Without them, the conference can't even begin.
中国代表团拒绝出席。没有他们, 会议甚至无法开始
Now Styles is flying to Peking in a few hours./?
现在 Styles 几个小时后就要飞往北京
There's just a chance that he can
persuade them to change their minds.
他也许有机会说服他们改变主意
All right, Brigadier. So what's his problem?
好吧, 准将。那他那里有什么问题？
Well, he was working late last night,
down at Auderly...
他昨晚在 Auderly 工作到很晚...
Where's that?
Auderly 是什么地方？
Auderly, Miss Grant, is a Government owned
country house about fifty miles north of London/?
Auderly 是政府拥有的一栋乡村房子，在伦敦北面大约50英里
- where the conference is due to be held.
- Oh.
- 和平会议将在那里进行  - 哦
He suddenly started behaving... rather oddly./?
他突然开始表现得...相当奇怪
Seemed to think that someone
was trying to assassinate him.
似乎是觉得有人试图暗杀他
Any idea who?
知道是谁吗？
Some sort of "ghost" apparently.
看起来像是是某种 "鬼"
He said somebody attacked him and vanished.
他说有人袭击了他，然后就消失了
And you're absolutely certain that
he used the word "ghost"?
你完全确定他用了 "鬼" 这个词吗？
Oh yes. But afterwards he...
嗯是的，但随后他...
Miss Paget! What's going on here?!
Paget 小姐！这是在干什么？
These people are from UNIT, sir.
这些人来自 UNIT，先生
Who asked them to come here?
谁让他们来这里的？
I did - because of what happened yesterday.
我让的 - 因为昨晚发生的事情
Nothing happened yesterday.
昨晚没发生什么事
There seems to have been
some sort of incident, Sir Reginald?
似乎是发生了某种意外，Reginald 爵士？
Nothing of any importance.
没有什么重要的事
Well, if you could tell us what happened?
那，你可以告诉我们到底发生了什么吗？
I was working late. I must have dropped off.
我工作到很晚，然后肯定是睡着了
Freak gust of wind, blew some papers off my desk,
可怕的大风把我桌子上的一些文件吹掉了
I woke up rather confused,
I was picking up the papers /?
我迷迷糊糊地醒过来，开始捡那些文件
- when Miss Paget came in.
- But you did mention ghosts.
- 这个时候 Paget 小姐进来的  - 但你的确之前提到过“鬼魂”
Did I? Must have been having a nightmare.
有吗？我肯定是做了噩梦了
But the French windows weren't shut.
I closed them before I went to bed.
但落地窗没有关闭。我在上床之前是关了的
Then I must have opened them!
那肯定是我打开了它们！
Did you, er, did you also make
those marks on the floor over there?
是你, 呃, 是你在那边地板上留下了那些痕迹吗？
Muddy feet, Sir Reginald.
Someone was in here, you know.
泥脚印, Reginald 爵士。昨晚有人在这里, 你知道的
Are you accusing me of lying, sir?!
你是在指控我撒谎啰, 先生?!
Sir Reginald, you've obviously been
under considerable strain recently.
Reginald 爵士, 最近这段时间你的压力显然很大
Were you feeling at all unwell last night?
你昨晚没有不舒服的感觉吧？
I felt, and feel, perfectly well.
我昨晚和现在都感觉非常好
Now, if you'll excuse me, I've a lot to do.
I'm due at the airport in an hour.
现在, 请原谅, 我还有好多事情要做。一小时内要到机场
You've no objection to my men
searching the grounds?
你不反对我的人把这里搜查一遍吧？
None at all. Though I really don't know
what you hope to find.
完全不。虽然我真的不知道你想要找到什么
Sergeant!
中士！
Ah, he's in a bad way, poor chap.
You'd better get him to the hospital.
啊, 他情况不好, 可怜的家伙, 你最好把他送医院去
- Captain Yates...  - Right away, sir.
- Yates 队长...  - 马上, 先生
This is a new one on me.
What do you make of it, Doctor?
这我都没见过。你对它有什么想法，博士？
I'm not sure...
我不确定...
Sir?
头儿？
What've you got there, Benton?
你找到了什么，Benton？
No idea, sir.
不知道，头儿
It was hidden about fifty feet inside the tunnel.
它被藏在隧道里面50英尺的位置
Have you seen this before?
你以前见过这个吗？
Really Brigadier!
What sort of games are you playing?
真的吗, 准将！你到底在玩什么游戏？
It's not a game, sir.
It's our duty to protect you!
这不是游戏, 先生。我们有责任保护你！
I don't need your protection!
我不需要你们的保护！
Sir Reginald, we've just found a very severely
injured man down by the canal tunnel.
Reginald 爵士, 我们在运河隧道边发现一个严重受伤的人
Oh really? And what did he look like?
哦真的吗？他什么样子？
Thirty-fiveish, average build. He was wearing
a sort of guerilla combat suit.
大约25岁, 中等身材, 穿着一种迷彩作战服
- And carrying that gun.
- I am very sorry, gentlemen,
- 还带着枪  - 我很抱歉, 先生们
but I have rather more important things
on my mind at the moment.
但我这会儿想起还有更加重要的事情
- If you'll excuse me?
- I've arranged an escort to take you to the airport, sir.
- 抱歉呢  - 我安排几个人护送你到机场去, 爵士
Thank you, but it shouldn't be necessary.
谢谢你, 但这并没有必要
I'm sorry, sir, but I think it will!
抱歉, 爵士, 但我觉得有必要
Oh, if you insist.
哦, 你非得坚持
I'd like to get that gun down to the laboratory
and run a few tests on it.
我得把那把枪拿到实验室去做几个测试
Well, basically it's a form of ultra-sonic disintegrator.
好了, 基本上来说它是一种超声裂解枪
You mean a ray gun?
你是说射线枪？
That's right, Jo, I mean a ray gun.
说对了, Jo, 我的意思是射线枪
Only it's far more sophisticated than any weapon
yet invented on Earth. Now take a look at this.
只不过它比地球上说造的任何武器都复杂, 现在看着
Quite an effective little weapon, eh?
非常厉害的小武器, 是哈？
Doctor, you say this wasn't made on Earth.
Do you mean it comes from another planet?
博士, 你说它不是在地球上造的, 那就是说它来自其它星球？
Well that was my theory at first, yes.
这也是我一开始的想法, 是
But the metallurgical analysis shows that the,
er, iron constituent is very much of this world.
但是材料分析却表明, 它的钢铁成分是属于这个世界的
In fact, it was mined not very far from here
- North Wales.
事实上, 就来自离这里不远的地方 - 北威尔士
How do you explain that?
那你怎么解释？
Do you believe in ghosts, Brigadier?
你相信鬼魂吗, 准将？
Let's be serious, Doctor.
我们说正经的了, 博士
I am.
我很正经
Oh, come along, Doctor, come along.
哦, 得了, 博士, 拉倒吧
Oh, my mistake. I was forgetting
the unimaginative nature of the military mind.
哦, 我错了, 我忘记了一个军人的大脑是没有想象力的
But we saw a couple of "Amicus Seperatus"
a few moments ago, didn't we, Jo?
当我们在不久之前见到 Amicus Seperatus 现象了, 对不, Jo?
Did we?
有吗？
Yes, here in this laboratory.
是的, 就在这实验室
Oh, you mean when we...
哦, 你是说我们那时...
Mind you, they were manifestations
of a much more benevolent kind.
fixme
None of your clanking chains and chilly fingers!
But ghosts, none the less.
That was because you were playing around
with the time mechanism on the TARDIS, wasn't it?
那是因为你当时在折腾 TARDIS 的时间机制, 是吧？
Still can't get it to work, eh?
还是没法让它工作啊, 嗯？
Well, I can't get this thing to work, either.
是啊, 我也不能让它工作
But this is a form of, er, of time machine
of a very crude kind.
但这是一个, 呃, 时间机器, 比较粗糙的那种
How do you know?
你怎么知道？
Come over here. Look at this.
到这里来, 看看这个
Now what do you think that is?
你觉得这是什么？
Ooh, it's a... mini-dematerialisation circuit.
哦, 这是个...迷你型的反物质化电路
Top of the class, Jo.
Now then, pop this in here, like that.
优等生, Jo。既然如此, 把这个塞到这里, 这样
Now, as far as I can gather,
when you push this button, it should...
现在, 据我的推断, 一旦你按下这个按钮, 它就可以...
Good grief! It's working!
老天爷, 它可以工作了！
Sir?
头儿？
What is it?
什么事？
Time transmitter in operation, sir.
Twentieth Century Zone.
时间发射器在运转了, 头儿, 在20世纪区域
Can you fix the space-time coordinates?
你能锁定时空坐标吗？
Do be careful, Doctor!
小心点, 博士！
All right, Jo, all right.
没事的, Jo, 没事
- Well?  - No good, sir.
- 怎样  - 不行, 头儿
There was a transference, I think,
but the machine's cut out completely.
刚才有干扰, 我觉得, 然后机器就完全切断了
Continue scanning - and next time
you had better be more efficient!
继续扫描 - 下次你最好效率高点
Report!
报告！
Yes, I see. All right, sergeant.
You'd better report back to Captain Yates. Goodbye.
是的, 我明白, 没事, 中士。你最好报告给 Yates 队长, 再见
That was Benton. He was in the ambulance
with the man we found.
Benton, 他刚才跟我们找到的那个人一起在救护车上
Well?
怎么了？
Well according to him, that man just...
vanished, faded away
据他所说, 那个人刚刚...消失了, 慢慢淡出了
- like a ghost.  - Oh no!
- 像鬼一样  - 噢, 不！
Well, Doctor, what now?
那, 博士, 现在怎么办？
Well, everything that happens seems to
centre round Styles' house.
嗯, 发生的所有这些事似乎都是跟 Style 的房子有关的
Obviously.
这显然
And whoever tried to harm him
will probably try again.
那些试图伤害他的人, 很可能还会再次下手
Jo, how would you like to spend the night
in a haunted house?
Jo, 你觉得到闹鬼的房子里过一晚怎么样？
Wake up, Jo.
醒醒, Jo
It's all right. It's morning.
没什么事, 天亮了
Nothing's happened?
什么都没发生？
No, nothing at all.
没有, 完全没有
Jo! Jo!
Please! Turn that machine off
- or they'll kill all of us! Please!
拜托, 把那个机器关掉 - 不然他们会把我们都杀死！求你了
Sir?
头儿？
Yes?
怎么？
We've picked up that time transmitter again.
我们又识别到那个时间发射器了
You're sure?
你确定吗？
Yes, sir. Same frequency, same time...
time zone. Much stronger now.
是的, 头儿。同样的频率同样的时间..时区。现在信号强多了
Right. I want the exact space-time co-ordinates,
so whatever happens, don't lose it!
好, 我要确切的时空坐标, 所有不管发生什么, 不要跟丢了
What is your report?
你要报告什么？
We have a fix on the time transfer device.
我们已经锁定了那个时间传送装置
It is operating again in the twentieth century
time zone and it must be them.
它在20世纪区域再次开启, 肯定是他们
You have obtained the space-time co-ordinates?
你已经得到了时空坐标？
We're trying now. The trace is
much stronger this time.
我们正在尝试, 这次信号比较强
- There is every chance...
- You must not fail!
- 这次肯定有机会...  - 你必须成功！
Security forces are standing by.
安全部队已经在待命了
If we do get the co-ordinates,
what are your instructions?
如果我们拿到坐标, 你们有什么指示？
Whoever is operating the time machine
is an enemy of the Daleks.
不管是谁在操作那个时间机器, 他都是 Daleks 的敌人
All enemies of the Daleks must be destroyed!
Exterminate them!
而 Daleks 的所有敌人都必须消灭！终结他们！
Let him go.
让我走
Now then - turn off that machine.
既然如此, 关掉机器
I have to report that we have lost the trace.
It was operating only a few moments.
我不得不说我们跟丢了, 它仅仅只开启了一小会儿
We are not interested in excuses.
Find them! Find them! Find them!
我们对接口不感兴趣！找到他们, 找到他们, 找到他们！
No last words of repentance, Sir Reginald?
死到临头了你忏悔不, Reginald 爵士？
No, only that you're making one fundamental mistake...
不, 你犯了一个很基础的错误...
That is?
是什么?
A question of mistaken identity.
I am not Sir Reginald Styles.
你认错人了, 我不是 Reginald Styles 爵士
Is that the best you can do?
你最多也就只能这样？
But it's true! Sir Reginald...
但这是事实！Reginald 爵士他...
Sir Reginald is at this moment
many thousands of miles away -
Reginald 爵士这会儿正在千里之外
in Peking, to be precise.
确切地说, 在北京
You are lying.
你在撒谎
No, I'm not. He flew there yesterday.
不, 我没有。他昨天就飞过去了
I do not believe you.
我不相信你
It's all there in the paper in front of you.
Why don't you take a look?
这全都在你面前的报纸上, 你为什么不看一眼？
I'm sorry to disappoint you.
很抱歉让你失望了
It's a trick - kill him now!
这是个伎俩 - 现在就杀了他！
If you are not Sir Reginald Styles
如果你不是 Reginald Styles
who are you and what are you doing in his house?
那你是谁, 你在他的房子里做什么？
Well, believe it or believe it not,
I came here to see you.
嗯, 不知道你们信不信, 我是来见你们的
We're wasting time, Anat. Here, I'll do it.
我们这是在浪费时间, Anat。来, 我来下手
Who is in command of this mission?!
这次任务谁是指挥官？！
We are soldiers, not murderers.
Keep guard outside, I'll deal with these two.
我们是战士, 不是杀人犯。出去警戒, 我来对付这两个
I said out!
我说了出去
Now then, answer my question -
who are you and what are you doing here?
接下里, 回答我的问题 - 你是谁, 在这里做什么？
- I wanted to talk to you.  - Why?
- 我想来跟你们谈谈  - 为什么？
To find out where you came from.
And more to the point - when.
为了搞明白你们从哪里来, 更重要的是, 从何时来
- Two soldiers approach.  - Hide!
- 有两个士兵过来了  - 躲起来！
Down there!
下去!
Hurry!
快！
Captain Yates, sir, on four.
是 Yates 队长, 头儿, 四号线
I can't speak to him now.
我现在没法跟他通话
He says something very odd
is happening at Auderly House./56.4
他说 Auderly House 那边出了非常奇怪的事情
If you could have a quick word with him, sir?
你能更他简单说几句吗, 头儿？
All right.
好吧
Yes, what is it, Yates?
是我, 什么事, Yates？
A couple of my men missing, sir,
and the Doctor and Miss Grant -
有几个我的人不见了, 头儿, 还有博士和Grant小姐
- not a sign of them
- Look really, Yates,
- 他们一点踪迹没有  - 听着, 真的, Yate
I've got a major international crisis on.
I really haven't got time for any...
我这里有一个严重的国际危机, 我真的没时间来...
- Oh, Lethbridge-Stewart?
- Erm, yes, yes, that's right
- 哦, Lethbridge-Stewart?  - 呃, 是的是的，我就是
- Yes, it's the Minister here.
- One moment, sir.
- 是的, 部长在这里  - 稍等, 先生
Listen, Yates, search the grounds again
or report back to me - out!
听着 Yates, 再次搜一下地面, 回报结果给我 - 挂了！
Yes, Minister?
好了, 部长
Right, they're clear of the house. Have you finished?
好了, 他们撤离这栋房子了。你完成了吗？
- Yes.  - We must go.
- 是的  - 我们得走了
Quietly!
安静！
Oh, that's better.
噢, 好多了
You know, I've got a good mind
to let you stay like that!
你知道吧, 我最好让你保持那样！
So much more peaceful.
安静多了
In any case, even if I released you,
you'll probably ask me a lot of fool questions!
不管怎样, 如果我放开你, 你就很可能问我很多傻问题！
I've only got one question - who are they?
我就只有一个问题  - 他们是谁？
On the face of it, three rather desperate people.
一方面看, 是三个挺绝望的人
Well, they're criminals - they must be!
当然, 他们是罪犯 - 他们肯定是
Ah, you're prejudiced.
啊, 你这是偏见
Well, aren't you? They tried to kill you and me.
那你不是？他们试图杀了你和我
That's not in their favour, I'll admit.
那对他们也没什么好处, 我得承认
You know, we shouldn't really judge 'em
until we find out why they're here.
在我们搞明白他们为什么到这里来之前, 我们不能乱下断言
We are maintaining constant watch,
我们在持续监视
but there is no sign of any
time transference module in operation.
但没有发现时间传送模块运转的迹象
All criminal elements must be
tracked down and destroyed.
所有的犯罪行为必须要追踪到, 要消灭
Well, I am doing everything possible, but...
是的, 我正在尽一切可能, 但是...
They will have returned to the time zone
where the first criminal was eliminated.
他们将会返回原时区, 也就是第一个罪犯被消灭的地方
You will dispatch security forces to search for them.
你得派遣安全部队去搜寻
Of course... at once.
当然... 马上执行
And the new equipment?
那新设备呢？
The Time Vortex Magnetron is set to the frequency
of the module that was traced.
时间涡流磁控管的频率, 已经调到与被追踪的模块一致了
Anyone using that module will be diverted
in the space-time vortex and attracted here.
任何人使用那个模块, 都会被时空涡流转移到这里来
But only if that particular module is used?
但只有使用那个特定的模块才会这样吧？
It is necessary to know the frequency.
知道频率是很有必要的
But surely no one will use the module?
They must realise that we can trace them...
但肯定没人将会使用这个模块？他们肯定意识到我们可以...
Do not dispute with the Daleks!
The function of the human is to obey!
不要跟 Dalek 争辩！人类的功能就是服从！
Activate the Magnetron!
激活磁控管！
...to base. Intercept to base. Do you coordinate?/?
..呼叫基地, 拦截小组呼叫基地, 你们能定位吗？
Do you coordinate? Intercept...
你们能定位吗？拦截小组...
No good. There is a massive disturbance in the vortex.
没效果。涡流里面干扰太强了
We cannot fail again. This is our last chance.
我们不能再失败了, 这是我们最后的机会
We must get fresh orders.
The time coordinates are crucial.
我们必须获得最新的命令, 时间坐标非常关键
We cannot wait for new orders!
我们等不起新命令了！
Look, why don't I return to the tunnel?
There's better chance of contact there.
听着, 我为什么不回到隧道去？在那里联系的话机会大些
Right, Shura. Ask them...
对, Shura, 问问他们...
Why ask them anything?
Isn't it obvious what we must do?
为什么所有事情都要问他们？我们必须做什么不是很明显吗？
We wait here and kill Styles.
我们在这里等着 Styles 出现, 杀了他
And if we are detected?
如果我们被发现了了？
We hold those two as hostages.
We kill them if necessary.
我们拿这两个人做人质, 必要的话杀了他们
Get alternative orders.
去看看有没有新指令吧
Right.
好
What do you mean, missing?
你是什么意思, “失踪”？
Well, there's not a sign of them.
就是, 没有他们的任何踪迹
We searched the house and the grounds, sir.
我们搜索了房子, 还有地面, 头儿
The Doctor, Jo and a couple of my men - vanished.
博士, Jo, 还有我的几个人 - 都消失了
Now listen, Yates, I've been talking to the Minister.
给我听着, Yates, 我已经跟部长通过电话了
Styles seems to have pulled it off. The Chinese
have agreed to attend and the conference is on again.
Styles 似乎成功了, 中国同意出席, 会议又要召开了
Oh, when's it fixed for?
哦, 那定在什么时候？
Tomorrow night, so you see the spot this puts me in!
明天晚上, 所以你明白我现在的处境了吧？
Get me Auderly House!
给我接 Auderly House!
Where is he?
他在哪儿？
I told you, Anat.
我告诉过你, Anat
I just don't understand. I mean,
why don't they go back to September 12th
我就是搞不明白。我是说, 为什么他们不回到9月12号去
if that's where they want to be -
you know, have another go.
如果那是他们想去的日子的话 - 就是说, 再来一次
Well, that's the Blinovitch limitation effect.
哦, 那就是 Blinovitch 限制效应
The what?
什么效应？
On your feet, both of you!
站起来, 你们两个都是！
Honestly, sir. You're wasting your time -
he's not there.
说实话, 先生, 你是在浪费自己的时间 - 他并不在那儿
Hello? Hello?
哈啰？ 哈啰？
Doctor?
博士吗？
Yes?
哪位？
Lethbridge-Stewart.
是 Lethbridge-Stewart.
Ah.
啊
Is everything all right there?
那边一切都好吗？
Yes fine, Brigadier.
Yes, things couldn't be better.
是的都好, 准将, 是的, 不能更好了
Yates and Benton came to look for you.
Said the place was deserted.
Yates 和 Benton 过去找你, 说那个地方都没人了
Did they? Oh yes, we were probably
down the cellar at the time.
是吗？哦是了, 我们那会儿很可能正在酒窖里面
Old Styles keeps a remarkably
good selection of wines, you know.
老 Styles 收藏了很多不错的葡萄酒, 你知道吗？
Now listen, Doctor, you're sure that
everything is normal down at that house?
听着, 博士, 你确定那个房子里一切都正常？
Because Styles is coming back there tomorrow night.
因为 Styles 明天晚上就会回到那里去
Look, I... I don't think that's very wise, Brigadier...
哦, 我...我觉得那样不是太明智, 准将...
Well, why not if everything's all right?
啊, 为什么不明智, 既然一切都好？
It is all right, isn't it, Doctor?
Captain Yates was very concerned about you.
的确没事, 是吧, 博士？Yates 队长很担心你
Well, you tell Captain Yates not to worry,
everything's fine.
好, 你告诉 Yates 队长不用担心, 一切都好
And tell old Styles too, and the Prime Minister.
也告诉老 Styles, 还有首相
Right.
好的
Oh, and Brigadier?
哦, 对了准将？
Yes?
怎么？
Don't forget to tell it to the marines. Goodbye.
别忘了告诉 Marines, 再见
(Marines 即海军陆战队，博士这里是把它说得好像是某个人名似的)
There you are, sir. I said there was something wrong.
看吧, 头儿, 我就说这里有事
I'm going down to that house myself.
我要亲自到那栋房子去
Lay on a jeep for me, will you?
I'll meet you there later.
给我安排辆吉普, 好吗？我一会儿再哪里跟你汇合
He's coming! Sir Reginald Styles is coming here.
他要来了, Reginald 爵士要过来了
Well that surprises you? Well, I should have thought
with your insight into the future...
让你感到意外了吧？fixme
oh no, in your case, it'd be the past, wouldn't it?
哦不对, 在你看来, 应该是过去, 是吧？
The conference tomorrow night -
our dates were right after all.
会议是在明天晚上 - 我们的日期终究还是对了
All we have to do is to wait here
until he returns and then...
我们唯一要做的, 就是在这里等着他回来, 然后...
Right! Drop your guns! If you don't,
I'll smash this to pieces.
听着！放下你们的枪？如果不放, 我就把你们轰成渣
Jo, put that thing down.
I've only just got it in working order.
Jo, 把那个东西放下, 我只是让它勉强可以工作
I mean it.
我说真的
Stupid child! You do not know what you are doing!
蠢孩子！你知不知道自己在做什么！
Oh yes I do - you're going to let us both out
- or you'll be stranded here for ever.
噢我知道  - 要么你放我们俩出去, 要么你们就永远被困在这里
We don't need that machine. We have another one.
我们不需要那个机器, 我们另外有一个
The man who owned that machine is dead.
His body is back in our time zone.
那个机器的主人已经死了, 它的尸体就在我们时区
You're... bluffing.
你在...唬我呢？
Put it down and don't be silly!
把它放下, 别犯傻
Jo, do as she says.
Jo, 按她说的做
Drop it... drop it!
放下...放下!
Jo! Jo!
Look, can't you do anything?
嘿, 你就不能做点什么吗？
No, it's too late.
不能, 太迟了
Well, what... what's happened to her?
那, 什么...她这到底发生了什么？
Disintegrated, dispersed around the time vortex.
被分解了, 散到时间涡流里面去了
If she was lucky.
——这还算幸运的
And if she wasn't?
那如果她不幸运呢？
Re-embodied in the twenty-second century.
会在22世纪重组
Believe me, she would be better off dead.
相信我, 她最好是死了
You may go.
你可以走了
You see, they're really not as terrifying as they look.
你看, 他们真的并不像看起来那么可怕
What are they?
他们是什么？
Ogrons. They're a form of higher anthropoid.
Ogron, 他们是一种高级的类人猿
They used to live in scattered communities
on one of the outer planets.
他们以前分散居住在一颗系外行星上
They make very useful servants.
是很有用的奴仆
Servants? Well, what do they do?
奴仆？那, 他们做些什么？
Oh, we use them as... policemen.
哦, 我们用他们做...警察
They're very simple, very honest, very loyal.
他们都非常简单、诚实, 还很忠诚
Do please sit down.
请坐
Thank you.
谢谢你
Is this really the... twenty-second century?
这里真的是...22世纪？
Oh, don't worry. We can return you to your own time, /?
哦, 别担心, 我们可以把你送回你的时间
but, er, tell me Miss, erm?
但是, 告诉我, 你是...？
Grant, Jo Grant.
Grant, 我叫 Jo Grant
Miss Grant... these three people
who attacked you - what did you make of them?
Grant 小姐... 袭击你的这三个人 - 你怎么看他们？
Well, they were sort of... guerillas, I suppose.
唔, 他们像是...游击队员, 我觉得
They are cruel and ruthless fanatics.
他们是些残忍无情的狂热分子
You know who they are?
你知道他们是谁？
Unfortunately, yes. But what you don't know,
is how lucky you are
很不幸，知道。但你不知道的是，你有多幸运
that they didn't get rid of you straight away.
他们居然没有直接干掉你
They tried to kill the Doctor.
他们试图杀死博士
He's still with them, is he - this friend of yours?
他还跟他们在一起，是吧 - 你的这个朋友
Yes, they're holding him prisoner.
是的，他们把他扣押了
Then I am afraid he is in very grave danger.
那我觉得他的处境恐怕非常危险
But they've no reason to harm him!
They know he's the wrong man!
但他们没有理由伤害他! 他们知道要找的不是他!
You don't know these people!
We have spent years trying to track them down.
你不了解这些人! 我们花了多年时间试图追踪到他们
If you knew some of the terrifying crimes
they have been capable of!
要知道他们能犯下一些可怕的罪行!
If anyone stands in their way, they are without mercy.
如果有人挡了他们的道, 他们就毫不留情
I can believe it.
这我相信
However, there is a chance that
I may be able to save your friend.
不过，还是有一线可能我可以救下你的朋友
Could you?!
能吗？
I can try. There are means but I shall need your help.
我可以试试。是有一些方法，但我需要你的帮助
Well, how can I help?
好，我能帮上什么？
Well, first of all, I shall want to know exactly
where you came from... and when.
哦，首先，我得知道你确切地从哪里来...以及时间
Well, we were at Sir Reginald Styles' house,
about... fifty miles from London.
哦，我们当时在 Reginald Styles 爵士的房子...离伦敦大约50英里
Now, you've told me the year,
can you tell me the exact date?
现在，你告诉我年份，你能说出具体的日期吗？
That's easy - it was September the 13th.
那很容易 - 是9月13日
Excellent.
非常好
Now, you must be tired, you must be hungry.
We do have special guest rooms.
现在，你肯定累了也饿了。我们这里有特别的客人房间
Leave everything to me.
Oh, there is one last question...
一切都留给我吧。哦，还有最后一个问题...
these criminals - can you tell me exactly
where they entered your time?
这些罪犯 - 你能否告诉我，他们具体从何处进入你们的时间线？
I mean, did they manifest themselves in the house itself?
我是说，他们是在房子里面突然现身的吗？
I don't think so.
我觉得不是
Somewhere outside the house - some hiding place?
那是在房子外面某个地方 - 某个可以躲藏的地方？
I don't know for sure, but there's a tunnel
by a canal, not far from the house.
我不是太确定，但运河边有个隧道，离房子不太远
We found that... time machine there.
我们是在那里找到那个...时间机器的
A tunnel? Thank you.
I'll call you as soon as we have any news.
一个隧道？谢谢你。我们一有消息就会来叫你
You see? She trusts me implicitly.
看到了吗？她一来就信任我了
The criminals are using the tunnel as a transfer point.
那些罪犯在使用隧道作为传送点
We will prepare an ambush
in the twentieth-century time zone.
我们将在20世纪的时区准备一次伏击
We have security forces in the area.
我们在该地区有安全部队
With any luck, they will drive the guerillas
straight into our hands.
如果运气好的话, 他们会把游击队直接驱赶到我们手里
Anat! Look!
Anat! 快看！
Shoot!
开火！
Pull back!
撤回来
We can get through the library. Come!
我们可以穿过图书馆，快
Stay where you are! Boaz, get out!
呆着别的。Boaz, 出来
Boaz, come on!
Boaz, 快点！
Come on, Boaz, out! Out, out!
快，Boaz，出去！出去出去！
How do you do?
你好吗？
Doctor, what on earth's going on?
博士，这里到底怎么回事？
Thank you, Brigadier, for that timely intervention.
谢谢你, 准将, 感谢你的及时干预
Who is that creature.
那个怪物是什么东西
Yes, well, I'll explain about him later.
Excuse me, old chap, I'm in a hurry.
是的, 好吧, 我以后再解释他的事。对不起, 老伙计, 我赶时间
Get back! Get back!
回去！回去！
Please! Wait! I've got to talk to you!
拜托，等等！我要跟你们谈谈！
Keep away!
走开！
Exterminate!
终结！
_ or you'll be caught in the time field!
We warned you.
我们警告过你
Yes, yes, so you did.
是的，是的，是这样
This may come as a shock to you, but you've just
travelled two hundred years through time.
有一点可能会让你感到震惊, 但你刚刚穿越了两百年的时间
Thank you. But I'm probably more familiar
with the concept of time travel than you are.
谢谢。但我可能比你更熟悉时间旅行的概念
Now wait a minute.
Before the time transference, I saw a Dalek.
现在等一下，在时间转移之前, 我看到了一个 Dalek
- You know of the Daleks?  - Indeed I do.
- 你知道 Dalek ？ - 我确实知道
I know them only too well.
They've been my bitterest enemy for many years.
我太了解他们了。他们多年来一直是我最痛苦的敌人
Then you're a fool to have
let yourself be brought here!
那你让自己被带到这里来，就太傻了
Look, I came here in order to find Miss Jo Grant.
听着，我来这里是为了找到 Jo Geant 小姐
I told you, she's probably dead.
我告诉过你, 她可能已经死了
But as long as there's a chance...
但只要还有一线可能...
Come on, Anat.
快点，Anat
Wait a minute - what is my best way of finding her?
等一下 - 我找到她的最好方法是什么？
That's your problem.
那是你的问题
We can't just leave him!
我们不能抛下他！
I can - come!
我能 - 走！
Run, Doctor - run!
跑，博士 - 快跑！
Report!
汇报！
The security guards have combed the tunnels.
They've found nothing.
保安已经对隧道进行了排查。他们什么也没发现
You have failed the Daleks!
You will be punished!
你辜负了 Dalek! 你将会受到惩罚!
The fault is not mine!
Your security guards let them get away.
错不是我的! 你们的警卫让他们跑了
- Those creatures are useless!
- They are loyal to the Daleks.
- 那些生物一点用没有!  - 他们对 Dalek 很忠诚
As loyal as they are stupid!
They will never be a match for human guerillas.
同样也很愚蠢! 他们永远不会是人类游击队的对手
No one can succeed who opposes the Daleks.
跟 Dalek 作对的人没一个成功
For every guerilla cell that you destroy,
another one springs up.
你每消灭一个游击队成员, 另一个又站起来了
They have stolen your time machines
and copied them.
他们偷了你们的时间机器, 还复制了它们
They steal your weapons, your explosives.
他们偷了你们的武器，你们的炸药
These criminals will be exterminated.
The Daleks will destroy them.
这些罪犯将会被终结。Dalek 将摧毁他们
If only you would let me recruit
more human security guards...
要是你们能让我招募更多的人类保安就好了...
Humans are treacherous and unreliable!
人类都很狡猾，不可靠!
Not all humans. I have served you faithfully.
并非所有人这样，我就一直忠实地为你们服务
Do not dispute with the Daleks!
Obey without question!
不要与 Dalek 争辩! 毫无疑问地服从!
Very well. There was one... curious thing.
好吧。有一件...奇特的事情
The girl referred to a companion in her own time zone.
那个女孩提到她那个时区的一个同伴
She called him... "the Doctor".
她称呼他为...“博士”
Doctor?! Did you say "Doctor"?!
博士?! 你刚才是说了“博士”吗？
He appears to have got through to our time.
He was seen by the guards.
他似乎也穿越到我们这个时代了, 警卫看见他了
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks!
He must be found at once and exterminated!
博士是 Dalek 的敌人！必须立刻找到他, 予以终结！
Don't gloss over it, Anat, we failed!
别掩饰了, Anat, 我们失败了！
We had no choice once our plan was known to them.
一旦我们的计划被他们所知晓, 我们就没有选择了
If you'd listened to me,
we still could have done what was needed.
如果你当初听我的, 我们可能已经完成所需要做的了
We did all we could!
我们已经尽了我们所能！
Monia, our orders were to eliminate Styles, right?
Monia, 我们的命令是消灭 Styles, 对吧？
Yes, but you failed.
是的, 但你失败了
We could have succeeded.
我们本来可以胜利的
Then why didn't you?
那为什么你们没有？
He wasn't there! Security guards found us.
他不在那里！保安队又找到了我们
But Anat went soft.
但是 Anat 心软了
Be quiet.
闭嘴
The trouble with you, Boaz is...
你的问题，Boaz，是...
Both of you! We have to think now.
The situation is different.
你俩都闭嘴！我们必须得想想了，处境不同了
As I see it, it's exactly the same -
we still have a job to do.
就我所见，完全一样，我们还是有活要干
No. There may be other ways.
I've had a report from one of our contacts.
不，可能有其它的路子。我收到一个线人的报告
A girl has been captured.
They're holding her prisoner at the control centre.
他们抓住了一个女孩儿，正把她扣押在控制中心
The same girl - the one who operated
the time module at Styles' house?
就那个女孩儿吗？就在 Styles 房子里打开了时间模块的那个？
It fits your description.
跟你的描述相符
Well, at least she's alive.
哦，至少她还活着
In the hands of the Daleks? She won't live long.
在 Dalek 的手上？她活不长了
Can she tell them anything?
她会给他们透露什么吗？
Nothing of importance.
Have they picked up that Doctor yet?
没什么重要的。他们已经找到了博士没有？
Not yet. It's only a matter of time.
还没有，不过只是时间的问题
Move! Move! Come along there, you scum!
走！快走！到那边去，你们这些渣子
Move! Come along there, move! Move! Go on!
走！到那边去，走！继续！
Well?
怎样？
Been captured. Taken for processing.
We must rescue him.
被抓住了，被带去处理。我们必须救他
Rescue him? Are you mad?! From there?
救他？你疯了？到那儿去救？
I say we must!
我说了必须！
Suicide.
自杀
Are you afraid?
你害怕了？
Me? Of course I am. I'm not a fool.
What is he to us?
我？当然害怕，我又不是傻子。他是我们什么人？
We have fresh information from
one of our contacts at control centre.
我们从控制中心的线人那里收到了新消息
He is the sworn enemy of the Daleks.
He is the one man they're afraid of - don't you see?
他是 Dalek 的宿敌，是他们所害怕的一个人，你明白了吗？
It's our only hope. If we don't act quickly,
it may be too late.
这是我们仅有的希望。不过我们不赶紧行动, 恐怕就来不及了
You are the Doctor! You are an enemy of the Daleks!
你是博士！你是 Dalek 的敌人！
Now you are in our power! You will be exterminated!
现在你在我们手上了！你将被终结！
You will be exterminated! You will be exterminated!
你将被终结！你将被终结！你将被终结！你将被终结！
Stop! You mustn't kill him!
停下！你们不能杀了他！
- Be silent.
- Don't you realise he can help us?
- 安静  - 你们没有意识到他可以帮助我们吗？
The Doctor is an enemy of the Daleks.
博士是 Daleks 的敌人
How can he help us?
他怎么可能帮助我们？
He is our contact with the guerrillas.
He has valuable information.
他是我们与游击队的联系人, 有宝贵的信息
- You have proof of this?
- I know he's working for them.
- 你有证据吗？  - 我知道他在为他们工作
We will force the truth from him
with the mind analysis machine.
我们可以把真相逼出来, 对他使用思维分析器
But look at him!
看看他！
You've practically killed him just
getting a simple admission of identity.
你们几乎把他弄死了, 他也才坦白承认他的身份而已
He'll die before he tells you anything else.
他在告诉你们任何其它事情之前, 就会死掉了
What is your plan?
你的计划是什么？
Let me interrogate him.
让我来审讯他
Why should you be more successful?
你凭什么就能更成功？
Because I understand human psychology.
因为我懂得人类的心理
I shall be able to gain his confidence.
我将能得到他的信任
To put pressure on him through the girl.
通过那个女孩儿来给他施加压力
By the time I have finished with him,
我跟他一结束
I shall be able to crush the guerrilla
organisation entirely!
我就可以游击队整个碾压掉了！
Release him.
放了他
Now, the control centre is here.
好了, 这就是控制中心
As far as we know, they're being held
prisoner in this block here.
就我们所知, 他们把俘虏扣押在这个区域
And how do we get through?
那我们怎么进去？
The disused underground railway of the old city.
旧城废弃的地下铁路
There's an exit right by this wall.
那边墙边有个出口
I know the Doctor would help you if he could.
我知道博士会尽力帮助你
I am trying to help him!
I've already saved his life.
我正在尽力帮他！我已经救了他的命
Yes, for your own purposes.
是的, 为了你自己的目的
Look, if you do not tell me where they operate from,
what their plans are,
听着, 如果你不告诉我他们在哪里运作, 计划是什么
then the Daleks will destroy both of you.
那 Dalek 就是消灭你们两个
I don't doubt it.
我不怀疑
Do you value life so little?
你如此轻视生命吗？
On the contrary, I value it enormously.
恰恰相反, 我非常珍视它
The Daleks will kill us whatever we tell you.
不管我们告诉你什么, Dalek 都会杀了我们
Not if you cooperate with them.
如果你们跟他们合作的话, 就不会
As you cooperate with them?
像你一样跟他们合作？
Do you really think that makes any difference?
你真觉得这有什么不同？
- They can be reasonable!
- Reasonable?
- 他们不是讲理的？  - 讲理？
They tolerate you as long as you're useful to them.
他们容忍你, 是你对他们还有用
I am a senior government official.
我是政府高官
You, sir, you, sir, are a traitor!
你, 先生, 你, 是一名叛徒！
You're a Quisling!
你是卖国贼！
You do not understand!
你并不明白！
We have helped make things better for the others.
我们帮忙让别人过得更好
We have gained concessions. I have saved lives!
我们获得了 Dalek 的妥协, 我拯救了生命！
Wouldn't you have helped more
by organising the fight against them?
如果你组织人跟他们斗, 不是会帮助更多人吗？
No one can fight against the Daleks.
没人能跟 Dalek 斗
That's not what your criminal guerrillas
seem to think, is it?
你那些游击队罪犯可不这么想, 是吧？
A handful of fanatics?
那群疯子？
Most of them have been killed already.
他们的大多数都已经被杀了
I assure you, there is nothing
they can do to change things.
我向你保证, 没有他们可以改变的事情
- Exterminate! Exterminate! Exterminate!
- Anat, look out!
- 终结！终结！终结！  - Anat, 小心!
Come! We must reach the control centre, come!
快, 我们必须赶到控制中心, 来！
No! Come! Come!
不, 快, 快！
For the last time, I tell you
I haven't got any information.
最后一次我跟你说, 我没有任何信息
And quite frankly, even if I had,
I wouldn't give it to you!
而且非常坦白地说, 即使我有, 也不会给你！
- Right, stay where you are!  - Guards!
- 好, 待着别动！  - 警卫！
Guards? You have no guards. They're all dead.
警卫？你没有警卫了, 他们都死了
- Are you all right?  - Yes, thank you.
- 你没事吧？  - 是的, 谢谢你
- All the better for seeing you.
- You're coming with us.
- 见到你们太好了  - 你们跟我们走
No harm must come to these two.
Too much depends on them.
保护好他们俩不受伤, 太多事情取决于他们
- As for you, my friend...
- Put that gun down!
- 至于你, 我的朋友...  - 把枪放下！
There's no point in murdering him.
杀了他没有意义
You don't know how much blood
there is on his hands.
你不知道他手上有多少血
Nevertheless, he's not your real enemy.
不管怎样, 他不是你们真正的敌人
He's helped the Daleks. He's worked for them!
他在帮 Dalek, 他为他们工作！
They would always have found someone.
他们总是能找到一个人的
Now, just leave him.
现在, 留下他吧
Right, let's go.
好了, 我们走
- But how do you know this?
- Oh, there are books.
- 但你们怎么知道这个  - 哦, 有书啊
Even during the wars, people found time
to study, to write about it.
就是在战争期间, 人们还是能找到时间研究、记录这事
What to you has not yet happened
is to us history.
对于你们还没有发生的事情, 对于我们已经是历史了
This history of yours,
it talks about Sir Reginald Styles?
你们的这个历史, 它说到了 Reginald Styles 爵士？
Oh, yeah, he pretended to be working for peace,
哦, 是的, 他假装为和平而工作
but really he just wanted power for himself.
但实际上他只是为他自己争取权力
So the conference he called was just a trick?
所以他召集的会议只是一个诡计？
He managed to lure the world leaders to
a remote country house
他设法把各国领导人骗到一个偏远的乡村房子里
and he pretended they needed absolute quiet
if the meeting was to succeed.
然后假装说他们需要绝对的安静, 否则会议没法成功
But then, there was a devastating explosion...
但是接下来, 就发生了一场毁灭性的爆炸...
And Styles was killed with the others.
然后 Styles 就跟其他人一起炸死了
He must have set a bomb and mistimed the charge.
他肯定是安放了一个炸弹, 但把时间设错了
There were accusations, counter-accusations,
然后就出现了指控、反指控
and then the wars began. That was the turning point.
战争就爆发了, 那就成了转折点
But if this true, Sir Reginald Styles
must be completely round the bend!
但如果这是真的, Reginald Styles 爵士一定完全气疯了！
Er, so, you went back into our time
呃, 所以, 你们就回到我们的时间点
to kill Styles before he could carry out his plan?
就为了在 Styles 实施他的计划之前杀死他？
Right. We've been fighting the Daleks for years.
对, 我们跟 Dalek 斗了很多年
But it was hopeless.
但没什么希望
Eventually we must lose,
so we thought, what else can we do?
最终我们必然会输, 于是我们想, 我们还能做什么？
We learnt through one of our spies
我们通过一个间谍了解到
that the Daleks had succeeded
in creating a time machine.
Dalek 成功创造了一种时间机器
We even managed to steal a copy of
the plans, and we built one of our own,
我们甚至设法偷了一份设计图, 自己造了一台
so that we could go back
into history to the exact point
以便我们可以回到历史中的确切时间点
With one action, we could stop them.
只要一次行动, 我们就可以阻止他们
Mankind could have a chance
to take a new direction!
人类就有了一个机会走向新的方向！
But even now, the transfer isn't always stable.
但即使到现在, 时间转移并不总是稳定
People materialised in your time
and then just faded away.
人在你们的时间出现, 然后又慢慢消失
The ghost that Styles saw?
Styles 看到的那个鬼魂？
Somehow, somehow the Daleks
found what we were doing.
不知怎地, Dalek 发现了我们在做什么
And they sent Ogrons back into your time
after us and attacked one of our men.
他们派 Orgon 回到你们的时间追杀我们, 袭击了我们一个人
Well, that must have been the man
that we saw down by the canal tunnel.
哦, 那肯定就是在运河隧道边看见的那个人
You remember, Jo, the one who vanished
from the ambulance?
你还记得吗, Jo, 在救护车上消失的那个人？
Yes, we fixed on the tunnel
是的, 我们锁定了那个隧道
as a place that was stable
in your time and in ours.
那是在你们和我们的时间都稳定的一个地点
We used it as a transfer point.
Well, you know the rest.
我们把它用作了传送点, 喏, 剩下的你们都知道了
Yes, well there's... There's one thing
I don't quite understand and that is
是的, 不过还有...还有一件事情我不太明白, 那就是
why were you so keen to rescue us?
And believe me, we're grateful, but...
你们为什么这么热衷于救我们？相信我, 我很感激, 但是...
Well, you told us yourself,
you're an old enemy of the Daleks.
哦, 你自己跟我们说过, 你是 Dalek 的老敌人
- Yes?
- Then you will help us to beat them.
- 是吗？  - 而且你会帮助我们打败他们
What do you expect me to do?
你们期望我做什么？
Well, you can succeed where we've failed, Doctor.
就是, 在我们失败的地方获得成功, 博士
We want you to go back into your
own time and kill Styles.
我们期望你回到你的时间, 杀了 Styles
You're asking me to commit murder!
你们要求我去实施谋杀？
No! We're asking you to kill one man
and prevent millions more dying.
不！我们是在要求你去杀一人而救千千万万
- That is still murder.
- Isn't it worth it?
- 那还是谋杀  - 这样不值得吗？
- To save the human race from the Daleks?
- Yes, but would it?
- 就能从 Dalek 手中把人类救出来？  - 是的, 但能吗？
We've told you how it happened.
我们告诉你们了, 这一切是怎么开始的
But your history could be wrong, you know.
但你们的历史可能是错的, 你知道吗？
Now, listen, why don't you
send us back to our time?
现在, 听着, 为什么你不把我们送回我们的时间？
We know the future now,
maybe there are other things we can do?
我们现在已经知道了未来, 也许有其它事情我们可以做？
Monia, we're wasting valuable time!
Every minute that goes by...
Monia, 我们在浪费宝贵的时间！每流逝一分钟...
Doctor, will you help us? It's our only hope.
博士, 你会帮助我们吗？这是我们唯一的希望
I still can't believe that Sir Reginald
Styles is a ruthless murderer.
我还是无法相信 Reginald 爵士是一个冷血杀手
Yes, I agree, Jo.
是的, 我同意, Jo
Vain to the point of arrogance,
a trifle obstinate, perhaps,
but basically a good man.
但基本上还是个好人
So, if it happened, how did it happen?
所以, 如果那事发生了, 是怎么发生的呢？
Any of your people still in our time zone?
你们还有人在我们的时间区域吗？
- No.  - Well, Shura.
- 没有  - 还有 Shura
He left just to send a message and
we never saw nor heard from him again.
他离开我们去送一个信息, 我们就再也没有看到他, 没听到他
We assumed he must be dead.
我们估计他肯定死了
Look, please believe me,
I'm completely with you about the ends.
看, 请相信我, 我在最终目标上跟你们是完全一致的
I only disagree as to the means.
我只是不同意中间的手段
All right. What do you want to know?
好吧, 你想知道什么？
This mission of yours to the 20th century,
what did you take with you?
你们这次到20世纪的任务, 你们都带了什么东西过去？
The usual battle gear, radio, disintegrators...
- Any sabotage equipment?
- Only a few charges of Dalekenium.
Dalekenium?
It's a highly effective type of explosive.
We stole the formula from the Daleks.
- Could it destroy a house?
- What are you trying to say, Doctor?
Well, don't you see? This has happened before!
What has?
You went back to change history,
but you didn't change anything,
you became a part of it.
What are you talking about?
If Styles didn't cause that explosion,
somebody else did.
Well, obviously, but who...
Shura!
Isn't that exactly what he would have done?
One last suicidal attempt to carry out his orders?
It's possible, I suppose.
You're trapped in a temporal paradox!
Styles didn't cause that explosion
and start the wars,
you did it yourselves!
You have failed the Daleks.
The Doctor has escaped.
He will be recaptured. I swear it!
He must be found and destroyed.
He will attempt to return to his own time zone.
If those guerrillas are helping
him, they will use the tunnel
and I am setting up an ambush.
If you fail us again,
you will pay with your life.
This is your final chance.
I will go and supervise the operations myself.
Is everything ready?
Security forces have covered the whole tunnel.
Don't worry, they won't escape a second time.
So it has ended as I said it would.
Did I not tell you it was madness
to fight the Daleks?
Is it madness to want to see a world
free from their rule?
- It can't be done.
- Oh, yes it can.
And I can do it. Are you going to stop me?
Go. I will deal with these criminals myself.
I said go!
If only I could be sure.
You spoke of the war,
of its years of suffering and starvation.
Well, I can prevent all that happening, you know.
You saved my life. You could have let them kill me.
- Go, quickly.
- Thank you.
Jo, come here and stand by me.
Sergeant! They're here!
This is Sergeant Benton calling UNIT HQ.
Look, we've found them.
Will you get a Jeep over here pronto?
This way, Doctor.
I am sorry. They were too quick for us.
They escaped in the darkness.
You are lying You have betrayed the Daleks.
No! I told you before,
those security guards
are no match for humans.
You are a traitor to the Daleks.
You must be exterminated!
Who knows? I may have helped to exterminate you!
You have proved yourself worthy
to be the new Controller,
but be warned, the Daleks demand total loyalty
from those who serve them.
Of course.
We must follow them into
the 20th century time zone.
The peace conference must be destroyed.
War must break out.
The Dalek conquest of the planet Earth
must not be reversed!
Look, you're supposed to be in charge of security.
Kindly get on with your job
and leave me to get on with mine.
Brigadier! Brigadier,
get everybody out of this house at once!
Where the devil have you been?
Never mind all that.
Just clear this house immediately!
What's the man talking about?
Do as he says! Look, there isn't much time!
Locate and destroy the peace conference.
Exterminate!
Destroy the human resistance!
Eliminate all humans!
Exterminate!
Brigadier, get this man and all the
delegates out of this area immediately.
Use force if you have to!
Jo, you stay here.
- Sir Reginald, please?
- No, I will not permit it!
Shura!
Get out of here unless you want to die too!
I must kill Styles to prevent the war!
Shura, listen to me.
Styles and all the delegates
are already leaving this house.
You detonate that bomb and you'll be
sacrificing yourself for nothing.
Benton calling UNIT HQ,
we just can't hold them, sir!
Look, Benton, keep them back
as long as you can.
Sir Reginald, this house is under attack
by a hostile force.
You will please consider yourself
under my orders.
- Brigadier, I warn you...
- Now be quiet, sir!
- Captain Yates?
- Sir.
Get Sir Reginald and all the delegates
away from this area at once.
Locate and destroy the peace conference!
Doctor! The Daleks, they're coming into the house!
- Daleks? You're lying!
- No, she's not.
They've come back to make sure that
their version of history isn't changed.
- Is everybody out of the house?
- Yes, everyone but us.
Get out of here. Let them come in!
Leave them to me!
- No, no! You must come with us!
- You don't understand!
That's Dalekenium. It's the only thing
that's effective against the Daleks.
Well, couldn't we set a time fuse?
No, this stuff's too unstable.
There just isn't time.
This is something that I must do myself.
Now, get out!
- Very well.
- Out!
Greyhound to Trap One,
do you read me? Over. Greyhound to...
Tell your men to fall back.
Let the Daleks into the house.
Doctor, are you sure that...
It may not make military sense
but it's the only way.
All right. Brigadier to all units.
Let them pass! I say again, let them pass!
Re-group on the main road, out!
Exterminate!
Eliminate all humans. Exterminate!
The human delegates are inside the house.
Enter and destroy.
- Where are the delegates?
- Where is the man Styles?
They must be found and exterminated!
Oh, no, not this time.
This time it's going to be different!
Well, what happened?
Your conference has been saved, Sir Reginald.
Now it's up to you and your friends
to make sure it's a success.
- You still have a choice.
- Don't worry.
We all know what will happen if we fail.
So do we. We've seen it happen, haven't we, Jo?
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)